VINCENT OKEKE (CPM®, CSM®)

Phone: +44 73 4095 5799

Address: 288 Newland Avenue, HULL, HU5 2NB, United Kingdom (Open to relocation)

E-mail: okekevincent@gmail.com | Website: www.vincentokeke.com | LinkedIn: technocratvince

Profile Summary

I am a Certified ScrumMaster (CSM®) by Scrum Alliance and a Certified Product Manager (CSM®) by the prestigious AIPMM. I possess solid technical product management skills and offer a winning combination of digital product management, business analysis, and project management skills. With a deep understanding of agile methodologies (Scrum and Kanban) and a successful product delivery track record, I excel in driving business growth and ensuring customer satisfaction. Drawing upon my extensive technical product management expertise, and research skills, I excel in crafting comprehensive product roadmaps, managing product lifecycle, adeptly prioritising features, managing stakeholders' communications, and driving the development of innovative solutions.

Education

o 2022 – 2023 **University of Hull**

MSc Business Management (Completed)

○ 2014 – 2016: Lagos State University

Master in Human Resources and Industrial Relations (3.51 CGPA)

○ 2005 – 2009: Anambra State University

B.A in Mass Communications (Second Class Honours)

○ 2004 – 2005: Sithri Computer College

Diploma in Computer Studies

Skills

- o **Product Management:** Scrum and Kanban frameworks, Agile methodology, Product Development Lifecycle, Product Strategy, Market Research, Stakeholder Management, Leadership, etc.
- o **Product Tools:** Jira, Monday.com, ScrumDo, Roadmunk.
- User & Market Research: Hotjar, UserTesting, SurveyMonkey, Google Analytics, market research.
- o **Design tools:** Visio, Canva, Figma, InVision.
- Business Analysis: PowerBI, Microsoft Excel (with good knowledge of Microsoft Office tools)
- o **CRM:** ZohoCRM, SugarCRM, SalesForce.
- Database Administration: MySQL, MariaDB (using WorkBench and PhpMyAdmin).
- Community Management: AgoraPulse.
- o Cloud Computing: (AWS EC2 Management, S3, etc., Digital Ocean).
- CMS: WordPress.
- o **Adaptability:** Good ability to adapt swiftly and acquire new skills.
- Team Working: A team player with good leadership skills.
- Language & Communication: English (Advanced), good communication & negotiation skills.

Certifications

- Certified Product Manager (CPM®) (AIPMM, 2023)
- Certified ScrumMaster (CSM®) (Scrum Alliance, 2023)
- Business Analyst Diploma Level 6 (UK Public College, 2022)

Work Experience

Working At Speed Limited

Working at Speed Limited is an innovative learning and development company and operator of my5starcourses.com. A platform delivering National Vocational Qualification (NVQ) courses that are accredited under the UK's Regulated Qualifications Framework (RQF) and registered with UKRLP.

Product Manager-----Nov. 2022 – Date

Job Details and Achievements:

- Monitored product metrics, gathered user feedback, and conducted market research to optimize product performance and enhance user engagement.
- Defined detailed product requirements, user stories, and acceptance criteria, and conducted user testing, utilising an agile development process which led to successful product improvements.
- Utilising insights from student feedback, conducting comprehensive market research, and actively
 engaging with tutors and stakeholders, I successfully identified and formulated new product
 requirements that seamlessly aligned with our product roadmap.
- O I successfully led the development and launch of two Moodle-based plugins, leading to a significant enhancement in student satisfaction and a remarkable improvement in tutors' efficiency for accessing and grading assignments. This initiative also opened two new revenue streams by enabling students on the my5starcourses.com platform to be able to subscribe for their course access extension and subscribe for priority marking subscription (I was issued a Letter of Recommendation detailing these achievements).
- Currently working on an AI-based feedback grading system which will further enhance tutors' productivity, and improve the grading system as well as the overall learning and development outcomes.

DoviLearn

DoviLearn (www.dovilearn.com) is an online learning platform delivering high-quality microlearning courses for professional development.

Co-founder | Product Lead------ Dec. 2018 – Sep. 2022 Job Details and Achievements:

- Co-founded DoviLearn with a mission to revolutionize the education industry by leveraging innovative technology solutions. I developed a clear vision and strategy for the company, guiding the team towards a shared goal of providing accessible and quality education.
- o Product Development and Innovation: Led the product development process, from conceptualization to launch, by overseeing the entire product lifecycle. Designed and implemented a user-centric approach to develop and refine the platform, resulting in a highly engaging and effective learning experience.

- Successfully secured funding through an angel investor and financial grants to fuel the company's growth and product development. In 2021, DoviLearn emerged as the number one winner of the Oasis Innovation Challenge (OIC 2021) and received the highest grant cash prize.
- In 2018, I was listed in 'Bubbling Under' of Africa's Movers and Shakers of Corporate Online Learning by a UK publisher – Learning News. Link

Elab Academy

eLab Academy is an online learning platform providing medical laboratory courses and training.

Product Manager-----Nov. 2021 – Sep. 2022

Job Details and Achievements:

- Utilised Agile methodologies, such as Scrum, to manage product backlogs, plan and prioritise sprints, and facilitate efficient delivery of high-quality product increments.
- Led a customer-centric UX/UI design process for the web platform's front end (elabacademy.org), involving insights from students, tutors, and the product owner to develop and implement clear design requirements, resulting in an impactful final design outcome.
- Successfully managed the entire product lifecycle for the company's edtech platform, (elabacademy.org), driving heightened user engagement and customer contentment through strategic roadmap development, milestone achievement, and Agile-driven product enhancement.

Dovichi Worldwide Technology Company Limited

Dovichi Worldwide is a digital technology product-led and growth solutions company. It is the parent company of DoviLearn.

Product Owner-------Dec. 2018 – Sep. 2022

Job Details and Achievements:

- Prioritised and managed the product backlog based on business value, user feedback, and market insights, ensuring optimal use of development resources and timely delivery of high-value features.
- Served as the primary liaison between stakeholders, development teams, and end users, ensuring clear communication, alignment, and understanding of product vision and goals.

Unical Limited

Unicaf is a global leader providing online platform for higher education programmes to the underserved markets in the Sub-Saharan African region with more than 60, 000 students.

Marketing and Business Manager ------Jan. 2016 – Feb. 2018

Job Details and Achievements:

- o Conducted extensive market research and generated insightful reports for strategic decision-making, including data analysis to inform decision-making for improved product offerings and growth.
- Developed and implemented several digital campaigns, and managed field demo days, including visiting and engaging students to gather insightful feedback.
- Successfully introduced the Unicaf Corporate Scholarship Scheme (Unicaf CSS) and implemented data-driven strategies, resulting in a remarkable 20% increase in student enrollment and a substantial 15% surge in scholarship applications and was issued a letter of recommendation capturing this achievement (I was issued a Letter of Recommendation by Unicaf detailing some of these achievements).